Preliminary Inventory to the Charles T. R. Bohannan Papers 1915-1985
Hoover Institution Archives
Charles T. R. Bohannan papers
1915-1985
78063
Hoover Institution Archives
32 manuscript boxes, 3 oversize boxes, 1 card file box, 1 motion picture film reel (14.8 linear feet)
Correspondence, reports, writings, memoranda, manuals, minutes of meetings, printed matter, microfilm, and photographs, relating to counter-guerrilla military operations, especially in the Philippines (1947-1965), Vietnam (1961-1970), elsewhere in southeast Asia, and Colombia (1959-1960); the Allied occupation government in Japan; and communism, especially in the United States.
Bohannan, Charles T. R.
Access
Collection open for research.
The Hoover Institution Archives only allows access to copies of audiovisual items. To listen to sound recordings or to view videos or films during your visit, please contact the Archives at least two working days before your arrival. We will then advise you of the accessibility of the material you wish to see or hear. Please note that not all audiovisual material is immediately accessible.
Biography
Lieutenant colonel, United States Army; Rand Corporation consultant; counter-guerrilla expert.
Hukbong Mapagpalaya ng Bayan (Philippines); United States. Army--Officers.; Asia, Southeastern.; Colombia.; Communism--United States.; Communism.; Guerrilla warfare.; Guerrillas--Asia, Southeastern.; Guerrillas--Colombia.; Japan--History--Allied occupation, 1945-1952.; Japan.; Military assistance, American.; Moving-pictures.; Philippines.; United States--Armed Forces.; United States--Foreign relations.; United States--Politics and government.; Vietnam War, 1961-1975.; Vietnam.
- Part I
  - Standing Operating Procedure for Pacification, 9th Infantry Advisory Detachment, Supplement, 1965. (Box 1)
  - Reports of Government of Republic of Vietnam
  - Photocopies of memoranda and reports on Vietnam, 1963-1964
  - Reports by Agency for International Development (AID), U.S. Operations Missions (USOM) to Vietnam
  - Propaganda leaflets (Box 2)
  - Memoranda, USAID
  - Clippings from Congressional Record
  - Military Assistance Advisory Group (MAAG). Memoranda and correspondence
  - U.S. Information Agency (USIA) - Vietnam Unit. Reports on Vietnam and Southeast Asia
  - Propaganda leaflets (Box 3)
  - Reports
  - Translation of captured Viet Cong reports with interviews (Box 4)
  - Tape transcripts
  - Notes
  - Map
  - Writings of Charles T. R. Bohannan
  - Vietnam Province reports (Box 5)
  - Information reports on Vietnam
  - Draft of report by Bohannan entitled "Viet Cong"
  - Printed material in Vietnamese and English (Box 6)
  - Clippings (Box 7)
  - Reports
  - Correspondence
  - Michigan State University - Viet-Nam Advisory Group
    - The Study of a Vietnamese Rural Community - Sociology, by Gerald C. Hickey, Assisted by Mr. Bui-Quang-Da, 1960 January
    - The Study of a Vietnamese Rural Community - Administrative Activity. Annex: Village Government in Vietnam - A Survey of Historical Development, United States Department of State. Agency for International Development, Vol. II, Chapters VII-X and Annex, 1960 May.
    - Local Administration in Vietnam - Its Future Development, by Lloyd W. Woodruff. Report No. 3, Local Administration Series, 1961 June
    - Provincial Government in Vietnam - A Study of Vinh Long Province, by Jason L. Finkle and Tran-Van-Dinh. Report No. 4, Local Administration Series, 1961 August
  - Hukbalahap Insurgency, Philippine Islands, by Bohannan (?) (Box 8)
  - Reports
  - Printed material
  - Study of the National Liberation Front of South Vietnam, File No. G-10, The RAND Corporation, MACV J2
  - Memoranda on Vietnam and Southeast Asia (Box 9)
  - Orientation Handbook, USAID
  - Army Service Forces Manual, Civil Affairs Handbook, Japan, Section 2: Government and Administration, 1945 January (Box 10)
  - Reports and memoranda on Vietnam
  - Memorandum to: Whom It May Concern, from: A. H. Peterson. Subject: Pacification in Algeria, 1956-1958, 1964 March 3 (Box 11)
  - Memorandum to: The RAND Corporation, from: Charles T. R. Bohannan (RAND Consultant). Subject: Comments on RM-3878-ARPA, Pacification in Algeria, by David Galula, 1964 March 3
  - Republic of Vietnam, Armed Forces Ministry, No. 1752/QL/ND MACV Translation, 1964 November 11
  - Republic of Vietnam, No. 332/QL. Prime Minister, MACV Translation, 1964 November 11
  - Supplement 3 to Standing Operating Procedures for Pacification (RF/PF), 9th Division Advisory Detachment, MACV, Draft
  - Supplement to Standing Operating Procedures for Pacification, 9th Division Advisory Detachment, MACV, Draft
  - Memorandum to: See distribution, from: W. C. Westmoreland. Subject: V.C. Captives, Ser. No. 0, 1753, 1964 December 7
  - Memorandum to: See distribution, from: Headquarters, U.S. Army Section, Military Assistance Advisory Group, Vietnam. Subject: Lessons Learned, Number 34: Railway Security (U), 1963 November 30
  - Memorandum to: See distribution, from: Headquarters, U.S. Army Section, Military Assistance Advisory Group, Vietnam. Subject: Lessons Learned, Number 36-Fires and Maneuver (U), 1964 February 4
  - Briefing by III Corps Tactical Zone, T GIA-Long Palace on On Experiences Gained from Operations Against Viet Cong Subterranean Warfare, 1963 September 20.
  - Republic of Vietnam, Ministry of Defense, Intelligence Report, 1964 February 6
  - Republic of Vietnam, Interministerial Committee for Strategic Hamlets, General Secretary, Permanent Bureau, Memorandum on Combat Experience within Enemy Liaison Corridors, 1963 July 5.
  - Translation Section, J2-MACV, Log No. 782. Translation per request of 5th Division. Circumstances: VC Liaison agent surrendered to "CHIEU HOI" office on, 1963 August 28
  - SIC Interrogation Report No. 163/, 63, 1963 December 13
  - United States Military Assistance Command, Vietnam, Subject: PW Nguyen Van Do (U), 1963 December 10.
  - Republic of Vietnam, Ministry of National Defense, General Headquarters, 1964 January 20. Intelligence Bulletin, IRS/AF - Vietnam Unit, M.395-Morale in North Vietnam (2 copies), 65, 1965 September 28.
  - Airgram, To Department of State, From: American Embassy, Saigon. Subject: Provincial Reporting: Memoranda on Binh Dinh Province, 1965 August 4
  - Memorandum from Leonard Maynard, Acting Ad/RA/USOM, To: R. W. Zollars, Prov. Rep. Quang Tin. Subject: General Situation Quang Tin Province, 1963 December 4
  - Republic of Vietnam, Ministry of Defense. Directive on Prisoners of War, Documents and Material captured on the battlefields, (photocopy), 1964 March 7
  - Headquarters, United States Military Assistance Command, Vietnam. Subject: V.C. Captives, (photocopy), 1964 December 7
  - Letter to General Khanh from W. C. Westmoreland, (photocopy), 1964 December 8
  - Republic of Vietnam, R.V.N.A.F. Special Forces, Team C.3/301/2, Intelligence Report, 1965 January 18
  - Viet-Cong Military Order of Battle, South of the 17th Parallel, as of Volume I and Volume II (in Vietnamese and English), 1965 March 31.
  - SIC Interrogation Report, Subject: Lao Dong Party Leadership in the RVN and DRVN, 1964 September 11
  - Republic of Vietnam, II CTZ, 21st DTA, G2-HQ, Transmittal slip, 1964 August 26
  - Land and Counter Insurgency in Vietnam, a draft paper by AID Consultant Charles T. R. Bohannan
  - Letter to Brigadier General Milton B. Adams from Solomon Silver, (carbon copy), 1964 January 17
  - Memorandum. Subject: Provincial Reporting: Taxation in Go Cong, 1964 September 1
  - Reports of USOM Provincial Representatives for Week Ending, 1964 September 24
  - Republic of Vietnam, Department of Defense, Study of VC Financial-Economic Capability in South Vietnam in, 1963, 1963 February 10
  - The Colombia Survey Team, Preliminary Report, Field Survey, See also Box 31, 1959 November-December. (Box 12)
  - Interdepartmental Survey Team to Colombia Preliminary Report (Minority), Joseph J. Koontz, Lieutenant Colonel, DOD Representative, 1960 February 9
  - Psychological Warfare Directorate, Department of Defense, Republic of Vietnam. Subject: Sector S5, 1963 March
  - Summary Assessment and Requirements of Strategic Hamlet Program, 1963 November 18
  - Project: Formation of a Federation - Vietnam, Laos, Cambodia. Purpose: To Gain Fighting Room. Saigon, F. P. Serong, 1964 April
  - Report of the Colombia Survey Team, Part III, Recommendations for U.S. Action, 1960 April
  - Colombian Survey, A Report of the Colombia Survey Team, 1960 April 5
  - Recommendations for Colombian Action, Appendices. See also box 31 re Colombia Survey Team
  - Rural Rehabilitation and Pacification, 1964 July 2 (Box 13)
  - Report by Colonel F. P. Serong to General Paul D. Harkins, COMUSMACV, "Situation in South Vietnam Following Change of Government,", November 1963
  - Airgram to Department of State from American Consulate, Hue. Subject: A View from Hue, 1964 June 29
  - Draft of USOM/Rural Affairs, The Situation in the Delta, (2 copies), 1963 September 26
  - Report of the Colombia Survey Team, Part I, Colombian Survey, 1959 October-December, 1960 April
- Part II
  - Vietnam (Box 14-19.)
  - Philippines (Box 19-20.)
  - South-East Asia (Box 20)
  - Printed matter (Box 21)
  - U.S. politics and communism (Box 22-23.)
  - Scrapbooks (Box 24-25.)
  - Newspaper issues (Box 25-26.)
  - Writings relating to Vietnam,; photographs and miscellany, 1934-1953, 1962-1964 (Box 27)
  - Philippines material (Box 28)
    - 1. CIC Biodata Reports, US Form 603, 1135th CIC Det., 1947-1948
    - 2. Malacanan Intelligence Division re Roster Philippine-American Guerrilla Unit, 1947
    - 3. Ambush of Mrs. Quezon and Party, 1948-1949
    - 4. Chinese Communists, Philippines, 1949
    - 5. Bicol Recon. Report, 1952
    - 6. Miscellaneous perssonal biographical data, Reports: CSS/OSI/SIG, 1953
    - 7. Same
    - 8. Report: Tarue,; also 1956 Report, 1953
    - 9. Intelligence reports, Philippines/Bohannan, 1953
    - 10. Intelligence Reorganization, Philippines/Lambeck, 1955
    - 11. Freedom Company Philippines; articles and by-laws, 1954-1957
    - 12. ECCOI Prospectus (formerly Freedom Co.)
    - 13. Freedom Co. Philippines and Philippines/Vietnam Veterans, 1953-1955
    - 14. Freedom Co. Philippines, photo album, anniversary party, Saigon, 1965
    - 15. Elections Philippines/Robot Statistics Report, 1962 (Box 29)
    - 16. Veterans Federation Philippines, and Philippines Veterans Bank, 1963-1965
    - 17. Peace and Order, 1968
    - 18. Miscellany, including Mrs. Macapagal's letter to constituents, (translation), 1954-1970
    - 19. Catholic Viewpoint: CRS, MASSA plus Mijares Defects, 1975
    - 20. PKP Five Year Project; statistics of atrocities, 1965-1967
    - 21. List of microfilms
      General note
      All extant microfilm is in box 32
    - 22. Photographs
      - I. Operation Four Roses
      - II. Operation Dragnet
      - III. 7th BCT Training Program and Operation Biak na Bato
      - IV. 7th BCT with Valeriano (Operation not identified)
      - V. Huk Camp, Pampanga; Stalin University flag; Huk Swamp Burning
      - VI. AFP Ruses
      - VII. 2nd meeting Taruc and Aquino
      - VIII. Namfrel poses shots, 1951
      - IX. Photographs with Ramon Magsaysay
      - X. Miscellaneous personalities, Philippines, 1950s
    - 23. Envelope of classified bulletins and papers, 1951
    - 24. Covert Evasion and Escape Manual, copy 288, 1952
    - 25. Tactics and Techniques of CI Operations, 1963, MAAG/VN, Revised, 1963 July 1
  - Miscellaneous publications (Box 30)
    - 1. Quarterly Summary II Corps/2nd Military Region, 2nd Quarters VN, 1970
    - 2. Resettlement and Food Control in Malaya, Riley Sunderland,; memo RM-4173-1SA, The Rand Corporation, Copy 122. Prepared for Assistant Secretary of Defense and International Security Affairs, 1964
    - 3. Anti-Guerrilla Intelligence in Malaya,; Riley Sunderland, 1964; Memo RM-4172-1SA, The Rand Corporation, 1964 September, 1948-1960
    - 4. The American Military Advisor and his Foreign Counterpart: Vietnam, by G. C. Hickley, with assistance of W. P. Davison, 1965; Memo: RM-4482-ARPA The Rand Corporation, 1965 March
    - 5. The Sabotage Manual, Vol. 11, Techniques and Devices; Para Military Manual Field Handbook FM-54-800-1 Copy 39, 1954 May
    - 6. Organization, Equipment and Supplement of Regional Guerrilla Forces Handbook, No copy 00117, 1, 1953 June
    - 7. Covert Paramilitary Training Course (in brown binder)
    - 8. Edition Army Extension Course, Special Text, No 73, Military Intelligence Organization and Function, 1933
    - 9. Guerrilla Warfare, 1949
      - Partisans in the Soviet-German War, DW-05, Copy #50
      - Soviet Partisans Warfare since DW-02, Copy #98, 1941
    - 10. A guide for Guerrilla Leaders with Special Reference to Jungle Conditions, 1949?
    - 11. Report of Colombia Survey Team Part II, 1960 (Box 31)
    - Recommendations for Colombian Government Action, 1960 April
    - 12. Informe: Que Rinde EL Gobernader a la Honorable Asamblea Departmental an sus sesiones Ordinarias de, 1959, 1960
    - 13. Bohannan papers re Colombia, 1959-1960
  - 201 Material re Charles Louis Glazer, 0-1321625. Glazer was Liaison Officer to Roxas and to Quirine
    - 1. Copy of information in Roxas Administration's card file in Box 33 (information supplied in, 1985)
  - Xerox pages from Official Directories, 1945-1946
    - 2. Page Official Directory, 1, 1945
    - 3. Cover, Directory, Republic of the Philippines, 1946
    - 4. Page Directory, Republic of the Philippines, Office of the President, Malacanan, Executive Office Advisory Staff listing Glazer as US Army Liaison Officer, 3, 1946
  - Communications re Glazer's assignment
    - 5. N. P. Davis, Charge d'Affaires a.i. to the Secretary of State
    - 6. Maj. Gen. Geo. F. Moore, PHILRYCOM
    - 7. Manual Roxas, President, Republic of the Philippines
  - Letters of appreciation
    - 8. Geo. F. Moore, Maj. Gen., US Army
    - 9. Morris H. Marcus, Col., A.G.D.
    - 10. Geo. F. Moore, Major Gen., US Army, personal note
    - 11. Edward G. Lansdale, Major USAF, Public Information Officer
  - Microfilm on the Philippines (Box 32)
    - R. L. Hoeksema, Communism in the Philippines, dissertation, Harvard University, 1956; One 35 mm microfilm reel
  - Newspapers, 1985; 5.0 issues
    - Philippine Inquirer, 1985 July 1-7
    - Veritas Newsmagazine, 1985 July 7
    - Ang Pahayagang Malaya, 1985 August 16
    - Manila Hotline volume II, numbers 21-22, until 1985 October 1
    - Mr. and Ms., 1985 July 26 - August 1
  - Card file, ROXAS Administration personalities and biographical data, Cabinet, Congress, Military, Government officials, businessmen, US citizens, other foreign nationals, 1946-1948: (Box 33)
  - Vietnam material (psychological operations, counter insurgency, Viet Cong propaganda, etc.) (Box 34)
    - 1. photos: President Ngo Dinh Diem at Palace, 1955
    - 2. photos: Operation Brotherhood Group with Oscar Arellano at Palace with President Ngo Dinh Diem, 1955
    - 3. "IVS" International Voluntary Svs; National Volunteer Svs; National Social Welfare Assembly; Study Group on Democratic Development; Proposal for Private Study Group on Southern Vietnam; List of Leaders AFL-CIO asked to participate, 1964
    - 4. Suggestions for Establishment of Provincial Intelligence Centers, 1965 March:
    - 5., 1965
      - August: Memo/The Rand Corporation, "Some Impressions of Viet Cong Vulnerabilities and Interim Report," by Goure and Thomson
      - December: "The Chieu Hoi Program as Seen Through Interviews of Viet Cong Defectors and Prisoners," by J. M. Carrier (i.e. Bohannan). Draft for The Rand Corporation
    - 6. reports/documents, 1962-1963
      - Southern Vietnam, The Political Relationship Between the Central Government and the Countryside, DSPPC, 1962 July:
      - Serong Report to Harkins: "Situation in South Vietnam following Change of Government" (two), 1963 November:
      - 1963 July: Translation of documents captured at An Xuyen, 1963 July 11
      - Training document captured by the 21st Division, ARVN (translations), 1963:
      - National Liberation Front of South Vietnam: Organization and Historic Days (translations), 1961:
      - Financing and Future of Counter Insurgency Effort in South Vietnam, 1963 April:
      - Extracts, Report CIO re VC Organizations in South Vietnam, 1963 June:
      - British Advisory Mission re Food Control, 1962 December:
      - John Moseley Report on Strategic Hamlets, 1962 September:
      - Memorandum re Control Measures, British Advisory Mission, 1962 December:
      - Observations, Squad Leader Training Course, Dinh Tuong Province, 1963 October:
      - Capt. P. F. Boyle re proposed "Silver Bullets Programs" to accelerate capitulation of VC Forces to RVN, 1963 October:
      - Psychological Operations Committee re Sino-Soviet Split and Propaganda Opportunities against the DRV, 1963 August:
    - 7. Cadres and Pacification (miscellaneous papers), 1965-1966
      - Rural Construction Cadres
      - Pacification Cadres
      - Monthly reports re Rural Construction Progress
      - Pacification Plan Outline: Techniques, memorandum working paper
      - Military Operations
      - Rural Reconstruction
      - Spoiling
      - Daniel Ellsberg, GVN Concepts of Rural Reconstruction, 1966 January:
      - Cadre Working Group and Report, memo and report, 1965 November
      - Special Study Group
      - Meeting with B. G. Nguyen Huu Co
    - 8. Pacification/Counter Insurgency (miscellany)
      - An Area Pacification Technique. Draft. Capt. Nguyen Van Long and Wankowicz: Effort to develop training program for C.I., 1964 November:
      - Pacification Operations in the 21st Infantry Division; Lt. Col. Cushman, 1965? January:
      - C.I. Campaign Evaluation, MACJ3, 1963 October:
      - Shortcoming and Present State of New Life Hamlets (translation), 1961 October:
      - Definition of Pacification; Taylor to AJD, 1964 October:
      - Seizing the Initiative; Hudson?, 1965 March:
      - General Estimate of C.I. In South Vietnam; R. G. del Prado, 1964 June:
      - Monthly report, 1964 March:
      - Annex F: Role and Problems of Sector Advisor, 1964 March:
      - Annex D: US and Vietnamese Province Rehabilitation Reports, 1964 March:
    - 9. Viet Cong propaganda file, VC, 1961-1962, Vietnam History Drawer/VC Section, 11 6D
      - VC 739 Manifest of South Vietnam Liberation Front (1st General Assembly)
      - VC 967 Extract from articles in the Chanh Nghia, "Message from Catholic Priests of North Vietnam to Catholic People of South Vietnam"
      - VC 671 "To Inhabitant of Quang Ngai, Quang Nam and Binh Dinh Provinces"
      - VC 621 Summary
      - VC 615 "The Little Girl from Luong Hoà"
      - VC 613 "The Extordinary Escape of Prince Souphanouvong and other Neo-Lao Haksat Leaders"
      - VC 608 "Appeal from the South Vietnam National Liberation Front's Committee of Ben-Tre Province"
      - VC 594 "The Spring Light"
      - VC 593 "Appeal to Officers, Enlisted Men and Civil Servants of the Southern Government in Ben-Tre Province"
      - VC 592 "Lessons Extracted from Conditions of Laos"
      - VC 589 Summary
      - VC 587 "Statement of South Vietnam Democratic Party"
      - VC 586 "A Press Conference Held by the Standing Sub-Committee, Central Committee of the People Front for Liberation of South Vietnam"
      - VC 814 "Stand Up And Be United"
      - VC 600 "The Comrade Recruit of Dien Bien Phu"
      - VC 561 Summary
      - VC 560 "Center Vietnam People's Victory"
      - VC 559 "National Liberation Front for Nhon Trach district's Letter to US-Diem Soldiers in Nhon-Trach's Posts"
      - VC 558 "Letter from Liberation Forces, Bien Hoa Province to Soldiers and Officers in South Vietnamese Army"
      - VC 557 US rubber boats are not unconquerable at all
      - VC 555 Appeal from National Liberation Front to Bac-Lieu Province armymen and civil servants in the Southern Puppet Government
      - VC 554 Appeal from National Liberation Front Committee of Bac-Lieu Province
      - VC 817 Official letter of Min. of Foreign Affairs to 103 countries denouncing plots of US imperialists to directly invade South Vietnam
      - VC 815 Vo Van Kinh and Nguyen Van Nho: Letter to unit mates, 22nd Division
      - VC 813 Appeal from Peoples Liberation Front for Thua Thien
      - VC 812 Enlisted men and officers in South Vietnam Armed Forces
      - VC 811 "99 ARVN Soldiers Captured in Gia Vut Battle Calling on ARVN to Turn Arms against US-Diem"
      - VC 810 "Dear Youngmen and Women in Thua Thien and Huc"
      - VC 799 "Unite Together and Rise up to Overthrow the Cruel Lackeys and Restore Right of Living, Liberty, Democracy and to Save Ourselves from the US and Diem Yoke"
      - VC 798 The United Liberation Youth Society of Long An Province
      - VC 796 Dear Young People in Thua Thien and Huc
      - VC 797 Welcome to the Victory of the Liberation Troops
      - VC 785 Statement of the Central Executive Committee of the Vietnam Peoples Revolutionary party concerning US open armed aggression in South Vietnam
      - VC 787 Southern People and Workers Note to Northern Government
      - VC 782 The Broad-day light pirates
      - VC 783 Enlisted men and officers
      - VC 780 Nguyen Thi Tu speech at conference of South Vietnam Peoples Liberation Front
      - VC 757 Dinh Cong Dam "Letter from New Delhi, Visit to Stand of Democratic Republic of Vietnam at the Indian Industrial Fair"
      - VC 755 Appeal to workers, farmers, laborers and hamlet SDC
      - VC 749 Peoples Front for Liberation of Thus-Thieu and Huc
      - VC 748 Letter from South Vietnam Peoples Liberation Front, South Central Vietnam
      - VC 564 Appeal from National Liberation Front Committee of Khanh-binh-Dong village
      - VC 581 The Young Communist
      - VC 569 (bis) Appeal from National Liberation Front's provisional committee of Binh-Dinh Province to government cadres at village and hamlet levels
      - VC 623 Ceremony of trooping the colors of the Peoples Front for Liberation of the south
      - VC 553 "What Place is Most Solid?"
      - VC 781 Speech delivered by Doctor Hung Van Cung on the Eve of Convening the First Congress of South Vietnam People's Liberation Front
    - 10. Report: R. Phillips to Killen on Viewpoint. Enclosures: Team Papers: Building a Political Base in Vietnam, Earl Young Report, Long An Province. Added: Summary of Information, by Bohannan, 1964 September 1, 1964 June 15
    - 11. Notebook: "Articles III HUAG" (see Declassified U.S. government records, box 35)
    - 12. "Huwag" (means "keep out" in Tagalog, or "don't touch") (Box 35)
      - "Civilian Irregular Defense Group" MACJ, 1963 January 21
      - "Counter Insurgency Course Student Report on Vietnam,", 1963 February
      - "USOM Comments on GAO Review of Economic Aid Program, Vietnam,", 1962 December
      - "USMACV Project Takeoff," Acceleration of Pacification Movement, 1967 July 21
      - "Coastal Junks of South Vietnam,", 1965 October 6
    - 13. Miscellany, 1964
      - Police file folders
      - Population and Resources Control
      - Orientation for Counter Insurgency, Employees/Stoneman
      - Task Force Vietnam
      - Land Reform
      - Rural Rehabilitation and Land Reform
    - 14. Valeriano's Special Report on South Vietnam, 1964 July
    - 15. Dr. PhanHuy Quat, Minister of Foreign Affairs, 1964
    - 16. Bui Diem, biographical sketch and correspondence, 1964
    - 17. Soro re Vietnam/ Psychological Operations, (Bohannan); Consultant background data, General, Bohannan, 1958-1959
    - 18., 1964-1965
      - Chieu Hoi: Msg Task Force Comments and Recommendations, 1965 July
      - Biographical data, Members Net Team, 1964? October
      - Short Course, Morale Action and Psychological Warfare Field Operations for 5th Bu Officers
      - DOD Report of Staff Visit, 1964 December